Toran Sahu

Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys

B. Tech (CSE), NIT Raipur

toran.sahu@yahoo.com, toransahooooo@gmail.com $+91\ 8602431733$

Summary

2 Years of total work experience at Infosys Ltd.

Currently working as Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys Ltd for IT projects in PLM domain. Responsible for understanding the business requirement, designing, implementing & delivering the solution as being the first point of contact for the client.

Have experienced many technologies during corporate projects - Oracle database, PL/SQL, Java, .Net, C#, Python, Siemens SIMATIC IT Interspec, Oracle Agile PLM, and Selerant's DevEX PLM.

Good understanding of data structures, database, algorithms, and business understanding coupled with sharp analytical and problem-solving skill.

Looking for a challenging work as well as fun. Want to be around professionals to learn as much as possible.

Experience

Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys

July 2017 to Present

Systems Engineer at Infosys

June 2015 to June 2017

Projects

ProConf – Interspec Data Migration– Mondelez International

Project	Interspec Data Migration (ProConf)
Customer	Mondelez International
Period	October 2016 to Present
Role	Subject Matter Expert
Description	ProConf project is about migration of some plants related data from its database to Selerant. The whole project includes 4 major parts: Extraction, Transformation, and Migration followed by Retirement.
Responsibilities	Managed the project single handedly
Skills acquired	PL/SQL, Java and C#.

Interspec Retirement – Kraft Foods

Project	Interspec Retirement
Customer	Kraft Foods
Period	December 2015 to September 2016
Role	PL/SQL, C# Developer
Description	Interspec retirement project was to migrate the whole data from Meridian's database to Oracle Agile. The whole project includes 4 major parts: Extraction, Transformation, and Migration followed by Retirement.
Responsibilities	PL/SQL and console application programming
Skills acquired	PL/SQL, Java and C#.

toran.sahu@yahoo.com

MS Excel Implementation of Regression Clustering

January 2015 to April 2015

An Application Software for attribute prediction of the data present in Excel file with minimal error estimation using regression clustering.

Technologies Used: Java2, MySQL, WEKA API, Apache POI

Algorithm Used: K-Means

Data Fragmentation for given Cluster Centers

July 2014 to December 2014

An Application Software for fragmentation of the data present in Excel file according to given cluster centers.

Technologies Used: Java2, MySQL

Library Management System

January 2013 to March 2013

An Application Software made in Java2 to manage the college library system.

Technologies Used: Java2, MySQL

Honors and Awards

Insta Award

Infosys Limited, Mar 2017

Certification awarded in appreciation of exceeding the client's expectations for the works assigned.

Insta Award

Infosys Limited, July 2016

Certification awarded in appreciation of quickly learning INTERSPEC tool, helping the team to build database queries & extraction process, hard-working, and dedicated nature.

Skills & Expertise

Python, Java, C, C#, Git, Linux, PL/SQL, SQL, NoSQL, Data Structures, Algorithm, HTML, MVC, PLM Tools

Education

National Institute of Technology Raipur

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech.), Computer Science & Engineering, 2011 - 2015

Grade: 6.96/10

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Malhar, Bilaspur (C.G.), 2010

12th, PCM, 2009 - 2010

Grade: 72%

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Malhar, Bilaspur (C.G.), 2008

10th, 2007 - 2008 Grade: 83.4%

toran.sahu@yahoo.com 2